Good morning friends, how are you all? I am
your friend MJ. I am back today with a new video. I
hope you are all healthy
and taking good care of yourselves. Are
you troubled by your mediclaim
agency? Is it
not receiving your calls? Do
you think you did not choose your mediclaim agent
correctly or have
taken a policy from the wrong agent?
If you are suffering from any of these problems, is there a
solution to it? Yes, the
solution is
insurance. There is
a provision under the medical insurance company in which you
can change your medical insurance agent. Is
n't this good news? You may
not be aware of this yet, but today you will get this information
and if required, you
can also change your medical insurance agent. So first, let us understand what
such
situations arise in which we can think of changing our medical
insurance agent.
If you are not getting good service,
if you need your medical insurance agent to
clarify some facts, to
understand some class,
or for some document submission, then he is
not giving you his time or he is giving
you such a problem.  It seems there is some personality
conflict, some underlying factor. You
want to say something but he is
not giving it to you, or there is a communication
gap between you and him. You are
not sharing your thoughts with him due to this underlying difference,
and he is creating a communication gap with you. So,
friends, in such a situation, this
provision is less for you. There is one more condition: the
insurance agent, who is going to have a
long-term association with you, has to take
you for granted.
As long as you remain associated with the company, you will keep
paying the company's premium. The
agent will continue to benefit from your premium in the form of commission.
He is probably
ignoring this thing. Perhaps he is taking you for granted.
Perhaps he is thinking
that you are helpless. No, my friend, this is
not your helplessness. If you are
facing any of these factors,
any of these problems, you have the right to change
your
medical insurance company's agent. If you have any problem with your medical insurance agent, you have the right to change your
medical insurance company's agent.
So what you have to do is,
45 days before the renewal of your policy, you will have to submit
a return application to your existing company and a
request letter mentioning
that you want to change your existing
medical insurance agent for this in this region.
Within 45 days, you will have to submit this to the company along with
your renewal cheque.
When you submit all these things, your
existing insurance company will
understand the reason and why you
want to change and will ask you
who you want to replace the existing agent with.
You will have to
share the details of the new agent with the company
and the company will change your agent
and then your problem will be solved. So, such a
small thing, so easy,
but due to lack of information, we used to think that
once we have taken the
policy from someone like this, now we cannot change it.
No, friends, you have this provision, the
company has given you this provision, you can invoke
this provision whenever you want,
but  This provision has to be made only
45 days before your policy renewal.
Along with D renewal cheque
means that if your policy is expiring on 31st March, then
within 45 days of that,
you have to give a return application to the company
and at the time of your renewal, you can change your agent by
giving the application along with D cheque or your renewal cheque. So
friends, this is a very common problem which
we all suffer from and somewhere we
feel that we are
not satisfied with this agent, he is
not giving us good service, he is
not helping us during our claim.
During the claim, when we make a claim, the
company sometimes
accepts our queries, asks us questions, sometimes it becomes so
technical that our
local understanding is not able to
reply. Due to lack of information, we give
wrong replies or do
not reply with proper documentary evidence, due to which our
claim gets stuck and gets delayed.  It goes away,
and then after that, there are many kinds of
psychological disturbances and
forms. So, if our agent
supports us, guides us on the right path to follow,
helps us,
properly helps us, how to
submit return documents,
what is right and what is not right, then
a good person would know all this
because he has
experience in clearing so many claims. When he
guides us properly and through his guidance,
our claim gets cleared easily in the insurance,
then
we feel that yes, this agent is good. But
if he does not guide us, then the work
which could have been done in less than a
week takes a month or even more
time, so our
problem becomes a very long stretch.
Therefore, friends, it is very important that
our medical insurance agent is on our
wavelength, matches our wavelength,
maintains good communication with us
and whenever we need him, he is easy to
contact at other points in time, easy to
reach.  If you are with us and are
in our radar then this
was a small video to tell you that you
can change the agent of your company and I
hope
you liked this basic video and if you liked it then like,
share and
subscribe to my channel, I am going to make it, in that
you will get
detailed information on portability and
how you can port your policy,
thank you friends